spacedaily.com 2019-05-04

# Privacy Statement - Space Media Network

**Privacy Statement**  

This Privacy Statement is applicable to all Space Media Network sites: Including [SpaceDaily.com](http://www.spacedaily.com/), [SpaceWar.com](http://www.spacewar.com/), [TerraDaily.com](http://www.terradaily.com/), [Energy-Daily.com](http://www.energy-daily.com/), [BiofuelDaily.com](http://www.biofueldaily.com/), [GPSDaily.com](http://www.gpsdaily.com/), [IndoDaily.com](http://www.indodaily.com/), [InternDaily.com](http://www.interndaily.com/), [MarsDaily.com](http://www.marsdaily.com/), [MoonDaily.com](http://www.moondaily.com/), [NanoDaily.com](http://www.nanodaily.com/), [NuclearPowerDaily.com](http://www.nuclearpowerdaily.com/), [RadarDaily.com](http://www.radardaily.com/), [RoboDaily.com](http://www.robodaily.com/), [RussoDaily.com](http://www.russodaily.com/), [SaturnDaily.com](http://www.saturndaily.com/), [SeedDaily.com](http://www.seeddaily.com/), [SinoDaily.com](http://www.sinodaily.com/), [SkyNightly.com](http://www.skynightly.com/), [SolarDaily.com](http://www.solardaily.com/), [SpaceMart.com](http://www.spacemart.com/), [Space-Travel.com](http://www.space-travel.com/), [WindDaily.com](http://www.winddaily.com/).

**General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) Statement  
** Space Media Network does not collect or retain data about you unless you subscribe to our newsletters at MailChimp.

Our advertisers use various cookies and the like to deliver the best ad banner available at one time.

All of our network advertising suppliers have their own GDPR policies (Legitimate Interest) that are designed to conform with EU regulations for data collection.

By using our websites you consent to the processes used by our websites and our advertisers. If you do not agree with this then you must stop using the websites from May 25, 2018.

The internet server the websites are hosted on - in the USA - collects log files of IP accesses. These logs are kept for apx 4 months before they are overwritten.

As of May 16, 2018 - Space Media Network no longer uses Google Analytics or any other similar traffic analysis software.

**Legitimate Interest: All Advertising Partners  
** Our advertiser partners, have a **LEGITIMATE INTEREST** to collect and profile personal data in the form of IP address and cookie ID from users on our website in order to provide targeted online advertising and ad measurement.

For more details including opt-out requests, access requests or complaints, please review our [privacy policy](http://spacedaily.com/privacy.html) or contact their data protection officer via [info@spacemedianetwork](mailto:info@spacemedianetwork.com)

**Google Privacy Statement  
** Google and the [DoubleClick DART cookie](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/faq.aspx):

\+ Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on your site.

\+ Google's use of the DART cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and/or other sites on the Internet.

\+ Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, click [here](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

**Tribal Fusion (Exponential Interactive, Inc) Privacy Statement  
** **Legitimate Interest: Exponential Interactive, Inc,** as our partner, have a legitimate interest to collect and profile personal data in the form of IP address and cookie ID from users on our website in order to provide targeted online advertising and ad measurement. For more details including opt-out requests, access requests or complaints, please review their [privacy policy](http://exponential.com/privacy/) or contact their data protection officer via [privacy@exponential.com](mailto:privacy@exponential.com) **ValueClick Privacy Statement  
** We partner with [ValueClick](http://valueclickmedia.com/member_privacy.shtml) to serve ads and/or collect certain information when you visit our website. ValueClick may use cookies or web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information during your visit to this website in order to help show advertisements on other websites likely to be more interesting to you. To learn more about this "behavioral advertising" practice or to opt-out of this use of your anonymous information, you can visit ValueClick privacy page [here](http://valueclickmedia.com/member_privacy.shtml).

**Konterra Privacy Statement  
** We partner with Kontera and the [Exponential Group](http://www.kontera.com/index.php/em-privacy-policy) to serve ads and/or collect certain information when you visit our website. Konterra and the Exponential Group may use cookies or web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information during your visit to this website in order to help show advertisements on other websites likely to be more interesting to you. To learn more about this "behavioral advertising" practice or to opt-out of this use of your anonymous information, you can visit [Exponential.com](http://www.kontera.com/index.php/em-privacy-policy) and learn more about cookie management.

**Space Media Network Privacy Statement  
** Space Media Network operates an in house advertising service that supports our various news sites. We do not collect or retain any information derived from specific cookies issued by our web servers to your computer. We do collect basic advertising usage data and our log files record all IP traffic to our web servers. No information about specific individual users is collected by our web servers. 

**Space Media Network**  
Space Media Network and its advertisers and affiliates are committed to protecting the privacy of its users. Below is information outlining our continued support for the responsible management of consumer information.

**In House and Third Party Advertising**  
In addition to our inhouse sales delivered by Space Media Network - we also use Tribal Fusion, Google Ad Sense, ValueClick, Real Media, Gorilla Nation, Ad Topics, and other third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements on this site and other sites about goods and services that may be of interest to you.

**Third Party Cookies**  
In the course of serving advertisements to this site, our third-party advertiser may place or recognize a unique "cookie" on your browser. (see previous point)

**Consumer Information**  
During the process of delivering an ad to you, Space Media Network or its advertising agents does not collect any personally identifiable information about you such as name, address, phone number, or e-mail address. However, Space Media Network and its advertising agents does obtain some types of non-personally identifiable information such as the Internet Service Provider you use to connect to the Internet, your browser type, or the type of computer operating system you use (Macintosh or Windows, for example). The information collected by Space Media Network and its advertising agents is used for the purpose of targeting ads and measuring ad effectiveness on behalf of our advertisers.

**Information Space Media Network Collects**  
To enable Space Media Network and its advertising agents to provide better targeting to you and appropriate reporting for our advertisers, Space Media Network and its advertising agents collects several types of non-personally-identifiable information about consumers who are served ads by the Space Media Network and its advertising agents Network. This information includes:

Your IP address: a unique number assigned to every computer on the Internet. The type of information that Space Media Network and its advertising agents can infer from the IP address is geographic location.

Your domain: e.g., .com, .net, or .edu. This is standard information that is available with all communication sent on the Internet.

Other information that Space Media Network and its advertising agents can infer consists of:

Operating system: e.g., Windows, DOS, Macintosh, or UNIX;

Browser version and type: e.g., Netscape Navigator or Internet Explorer;

Browser language: e.g., Java or Unix;

Internet Service Provider (ISP): e.g., MindSpring or AOL;

Clickstream information: Space Media Network and its advertising agents can infer how you use the sites and pages on the internet, and can infer your local time. If you have any questions, please contact us at info@spacemedianetwork.com .

In some cases, you may voluntarily provide personal information in response to a specific ad (this ad may ask you to fill out a survey or provide your zip code). If this does occur, Space Media Network or its advertising agents may collect this information on behalf of an advertiser. This information is used by an advertiser to respond to your request. In addition, Space Media Network or its agents may combine this information with other users' information and review it in an aggregate form to understand the type of individuals who view a specific type of ad or visit a particular kind of website.

**Data Collection and Opt Out Procedure**  
Space Media Network or its advertising agents may use "cookies" to enhance your experience on the web. Space Media Network cannot use these cookies to personally identify you in any way.

**What are cookies and why do we use them?**  
A cookie is a unique number that is provided to you the first time a Space Media Network advertising agent utilising this technology serves you an ad. While we believe cookies enhance your Internet experience by limiting the number of times you see the same ad and delivering more relevant content to you, they are not required for Space Media Network to deliver advertising banners to your web browser.

**If you do not want the benefit of a network cookie, there is a simple procedure to manually delete your cookies. Please consult your web browser's Help documentation for more information.**
